Czar Ian Curtiz Echavez

Home Address:

Email: czar.echavez@yahoo.co.uk

Alternative email: czare23@gmail.com

Mobile no.:

Website: https://czar-ec.github.io/

PROFILE

Junior Web Developer with 2 years of web development experience, as well as some experience with C++ and Java and have the ability to quickly learn new languages and tools when/if necessary. Also have interest in automation, DevOps, Machine Learning as well as Cybersecurity and very often tinker around with these. These projects can be found by exploring the website above.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web JavaScript, Typescript, Angular (5+), HTML, CSS (SCSS/SASS), Dojo, Electron

Testing Jasmine, Protractor, Cypress, JUnit, Cucumber (Gherkin)

Backend Java, C++, C#
DevOps Jenkins, TravisCI

Other Git, Apache Tomcat, NGINX, VS Code, Visual Studio, npm, AdobeXD, OBSStudio,

OpenShot Editor, Inkscape

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Web Developer at Envitia (August 2018 – Current)

- Creating front end solutions required by projects, using existing company software / assets, and adapting said item for use in the project or creating a new solution entirely
- Integrated Cucumber/Gherkin into company projects to allow for Behaviour Driven
 Development
- Integrated Cypress as a replacement End to End testing tool for Protractor, which sped up
 writing of tests and improved debugging of tests when failures occur
- Constantly experimenting with alternative tools to find better practices such as using NGINX
 as an alternative to Apache Tomcat
- Created UI designs which were shown to clients before development which were useful in identifying the wants and needs of the client(s) from the end software – saved cost on development

Student demonstrator at University of Reading (October 2017 – April 2018)

- Assisting lecturers with marking and helping students achieve the objectives for the Programming module's practical.
- Helping students solve problems with both their programming and the setup of their computers
- After results day, news from both students and lecturers said that most of the 1st Year class achieved 60% (2:1) or above for the module

EDUCATION

2015 - 2018:

University of Reading – BSc Computer Science (2:1)

Final Year project (dissertation) is the development of an epidemic simulator system which simulates the spread of a disease around different countries. The system also includes a scenario creator which allows users to create more scenarios the simulations can be run on. **Achieved 70%** (available at: https://github.com/Czar-Ec/ZEUS/tree/master/ZEUS VS)

2012 - 2015:

St. Wilfrid's School, Crawley - A Levels:

- AS: Computing (C), Mathematics (D)
- A2: IT (A), Physics (C), Chemistry (C)

St. Wilfrid's School, Crawley - 12 GCSE's ranging A - C including:

Mathematics (A), Triple Science (A), ICT (Distinction), English (C)

Central Sussex College, Crawley

Engineering BTEC Level 2 (Merit)

SKILLS

Communication:

- Constantly communicates with other team members to prevent merge issues / other problems caused by unexpected changes
- Able to convey work that is already done / needs to be done in cases of sickness

Teamwork:

- Can work as a part of a small or a large team and can easily integrate myself or other people into a group
- Able to use version control (Git) to be able to work in coordination with other developers

Other skills:

Bilingual; can speak both English and Tagalog. (English is primary language)

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Extracurricular activities:

Portfolio Website

Website referenced in the title. Acts as both the portfolio containing this CV and other extra items and as a testing platform for tools or frameworks.

Cyber Security Challenge UK

During July 2017, I took part in CSC UK's capture the flag event in which **my team finished in 2**nd **place.**

Game modification

In my spare time, I look at some game files and make modifications (usually text editing, sometimes tool assisted i.e. cheat engine) to observe how the changes affect the game behaviour. I usually do this to see how the game progression changes or how the changes affect the game mechanics (and of course, to enjoy the game)

REFERENCES

Simon Sherratt [Tutor] School of Systems Engineering University of Reading

Email: r.s.sherratt@reading.ac.uk

Phone: 0118 378 8588

Jamie Chandler [A Level IT Teacher]
St. Wilfrid's School, Crawley
Email: j.chandler@stwilfrids.com